A Guide to the William Faulkner Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10443
William Faulkner Collection 1908-1943
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10443
ca. 36 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the Library's microfilms of the William Faulkner manuscripts in its custody; the microfilm may be consulted by any interested party, and it will be lent through the interlibrary loan system. Materials are constantly added. Long-term loans may be arranged. Use of the microfilm will be restricted to the premises of the borrowing library. No loans will be made to individuals. Researchers should enquire of the Manuscripts Division concerning availability of microfilm of manuscripts that are pertinent to their work. Most of the literary manuscripts in our collections written by Faulkner, both holograph and typescript, have also been published in facsimile in William Faulkner Manuscripts, 25 vols (New York: Garland, 1986-87).
By the terms of the agreement by which the William Faulkner Foundation transferred the original manuscripts to the University, access to the original manuscripts is restricted (to ensure the survival of the physically-delicate originals) to doctoral candidates at the dissertation stage of their programs, and to certain mature scholars and critics. But even these researchers must demonstrate need to see the originals that goes beyond the requirements of most routine research. A doctoral candidate at the dissertation stage, or other qualified researcher who believes that his or her work requires access to the originals must correspond with the Curator of Manuscripts prior to arrival at the Library to obtain permission for access.
No microfilm, electrostatic, or other types of copies may be made of materials written by William Faulkner that are in our William Faulkner Collections. Other materials in the collections may be copied subject to the normal rules of the Library established under the conditions of the Copyright Act. All copying is performed by the Printing Services Department of the University.
Acquisition Information
A purchase by the Library on 16 February 1981.
Item Listing
- LETTERS
  - [ William Faulkner] to [Mr. Maud Falkner], [1943 Feb 21]; TLS 1 p.
    w/envelope
  - [ William Faulkner] to [Mrs. Maud Falkner], [1943 Feb 28]; TLS 1 p.
  - [ William Faulkner] to [Mrs. Maud Falkner], [1943 Apr 25?]; TLS 1 p.
  - [ William Faulkner] to [Mrs. Maud Falkner], n. d.; TLS 1 p.
  - Addressed to Mrs. Maud Faulkner in William Faulkner's hand, 1943 Apr 20; Envelope 1 item
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  - [ John Falkner, Jack Falkner, and Dean Falkner], 1914; Photographs 1 item (photograph item 560)
  - [ John Falkner, Jack Falkner, William Falkner and Dean Falkner], [1911]; Photograph 1 item (photograph item 561)
  - Dean Swift Falkner and "Nannie,", [1908]; Photograph 1 item (photograph item 562)
  - [ Sallie Murray Falkner], n. d.; Photograph 1 item (photograph item 563)
  - [ Sallie Murray Falkner], n. d.; Photograph 1 item (photograph item 564)
  - [ J. W. T. Falkner], [1915]; Photograph 1 item (photograph item 565)
  - William Faulkner, [1915]; Photograph 1 item (photograph 566)
  - William Faulkner in red hunting coat, inscribed "To Mutt & Chooky with love, Brother Will", n. d.; Photograph 1 item (photograph item 567)
  - Snapshots of Falkner family members, n. d.; Photographs 9 items (photograph items 568-576)
- MISCELLANEOUS
  - Windmill, by William Faulkner, Drawing (watercolor) 1 p.
  - "Le poilu," by [ Wiliam Faulkner], n. d.; Drawing (pencil) 1 p.
  - A sergeant, w/sketches of two soldiers on verso, by [ William Faulkner], n. d.; Drawing (pencil) 2 p.
  - An officer, w/drawing on verso, by [ William Faulkner], n. d.; Drawing (pencil) 2 p.
  - Pen and pencil sketch in hand of child [ William Faulkner?] and card to accompany a gift, signed "your loving son William,", Sketch and card 3 p.
  - From tablet on which drawings by William Faulkner were made, n. d.; Blank page 1 p.
  - For William Faulkner, 1910-1911; School report card 2 p.
  - For William Faulkner, 1911-1912; School report card 4 p.
  - For John Falkner, 1919-1911; School report card 2 p.
  - For John Falkner, 1912-1913; School report card 2 p.
  - For Murry Falkner, 1908-1909; School report card 2 p.
  - For Murry Falkner, 1911-1912; School report card 4 p.
  - For the " Royal Flying Corps--Canada" (printed form, not filled in), n. d.; Application form 4 p.
  - For "Une revelation apportee par Malraux prix goncourt,", 1933; Book jacket 1 p.